Guide to the Emil J. Dillon Papers, ca. 1873-1933
Department of Special Collections
- Series 6. Photographs, 3 linear ft.
  - Subseries 3. Family
    - Eddie [Edmund] Dillon, E. J. Dillon's grandson [8 of 8]1939-1947 (Box 3.2, Folder 23)
    - Elena Dillon, E. J. Dillon's wife1909-1910; undated (Box 3.2, Folder 24)
    - Gallaway Wilson, Alexander [Lex]Undated (Box 3.2, Folder 25)
    - Godson, Taisa1920-1946 Dec. 23 (Box 3.2, Folder 26)
      Note: incl. a letter.
    - Harold G. Dillon, E. J. Dillon's son [1 of 6]1899-undated (Box 3.2, Folder 27)
    - Harold G. Dillon, E. J. Dillon's son [2 of 6]Undated (Box 3.2, Folder 28)
    - Harold G. Dillon, E. J. Dillon's son [3 of 6]1910- undated (Box 3.2, Folder 29)
    - Harold G. Dillon, E. J. Dillon's son [4 of 6]Undated (Box 3.2, Folder 30)
    - Harold G. Dillon, E. J. Dillon's son [5 of 6]1920-undated (Box 3.2, Folder 31)
    - Kathleen Dillon, E. J. Dillon's wifeUndated (Box 3.3, Folder 1)
    - Lawrence, Jack1959 (Box 3.3, Folder 2)
    - Lucia, Dillon, E. J. Dillon's daughter-in-low [1 of 4]Undated (Box 3.3, Folder 3)
    - Lucia, Dillon, E. J. Dillon's daughter-in-low [2 of 4]Undated (Box 3.3, Folder 4)
    - Lucia, Dillon, E. J. Dillon's daughter-in-low [3 of 4]Undated (Box 3.3, Folder 5)
    - Lucia, Dillon, E. J. Dillon's daughter-in-low [4 of 4]Undated (Box 3.3, Folder 6)
    - Mary Dillon, E. J. Dillon's sister Undated (Box 3.3, Folder 7)
    - Menz, Thomas, Lucia Dillon's father Undated (Box 3.3, Folder 8)
      Note: incl. negative; photo of Merie Menz, Lucia's half sister.
    - Scott, Walter1921 Oct. (Box 3.3, Folder 9)
    - Smith, Alice & L.[?]1946 (Box 3.3, Folder 10)
    - Smith, Leo Michael1920 (Box 3.3, Folder 11)
    - Vareshina, Ekaterina Vasilievna [Katya]1929-1945 (Box 3.3, Folder 12)
    - Vareshina's sculptures [1 of 3]Undated (Box 3.3, Folder 13)
    - Vareshina's sculptures [2 of 3]1943-1948 (Box 3.3, Folder 14)
    - Vareshina's sculptures [3 of 3]1943-1948 (Box 3.3, Folder 15)
    - Vey, F. H.Undated (Box 3.3, Folder 16)
    - Vladimir Dillon, E. J. Dillon's son [1 of 6]1905 Oct. 11 (Box 3.3, Folder 17)
    - Vladimir Dillon, E. J. Dillon's son [2 of 6]1928 Dec. 3 (Box 3.3, Folder 18)
    - Vladimir Dillon, E. J. Dillon's son [with his wife Zena] [3 of 6]1920-1933 (Box 3.3, Folder 19)
    - Vladimir Dillon, E. J. Dillon's son [4 of 6]Undated (Box 3.3, Folder 20)
    - Vladimir Dillon, E. J. Dillon's son [with Constantin Dillon] [5 of 6]Undated (Box 3.3, Folder 21)
    - Vladimir Dillon, E. J. Dillon's son [6 of 6]Undated (Box 3.3, Folder 22)
    - Wall [?], Leslei1917 (Box 3.3, Folder 23)
    - Zena Dillon, E. J. Dillon's daughter-in-low1924 Aug. - 1928 Dec. 3 (Box 3.3, Folder 24)
    - Zucke, PaulUndated (Box 3.3, Folder 25)
    - Unidentified [1 of 18]1917 (Box 3.4, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified [2 of 18]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified [3 of 18]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified [4 of 18]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified [5 of 18]1935 Aug. 15 (Box 3.4, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified [6 of 18]1881-1897; undated (Box 3.4, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified [7 of 18]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified [8 of 18]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified [9 of 18]1910-undated (Box 3.4, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified [10 of 18]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified [11 of 18]1946-undated (Box 3.4, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified [12 of 18]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified [13 of 18]1908-1919-20; undated (Box 3.4, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified [14 of 18]1916-17; undated (Box 3.4, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified [15 of 18]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified [16 of 18]1908-1910 (Box 3.4, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified [17 of 18]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified [18 of 18]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 18)
    - MiscellaneousUndated (Box 3.4, Folder 19)
    - Negatives [1 of 5]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 20)
    - Negatives [2 of 5]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 21)
    - Negatives [3 of 5]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 22)
    - Negatives [4 of 5]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 23)
    - Negatives [5 of 5]Undated (Box 3.4, Folder 24)
    - E. J. Dillonn.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Portrait of E. J. Dillonn.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - E. J. Dillonn.d. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Headston on Michael Dillon's Grave [?]1892 [?] (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Lucia Dillon, E J. Dillon's Daughter-in-Lawn.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4. Albums
    - Constantin Dillon's family [1 of 3]1918-undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Constantin Dillon's family [2 of 3]1919-undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Constantin Dillon's family [3 of 3]Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Constantin Dillon's family & friends1909-1911; undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Series 7. Personal and Domestic, 2.5 linear ft.
  - Barbara & Betty Dillon's correspondence1924 Apr. 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Children's letters & cards [1 of 3]1892 Feb. 11 - 1894 March 17; includes undated materials (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Note: some materials are in Russian.
  - Children's letters & cards [2 of 3]1894 Sept. 15 - 1899 Apr. [n.d.]; includes no date/noyear materials. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Children's letters & cards [3 of 3]Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Constantin Dillon's correspondence [1 of 4]1893-1897 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Constantin Dillon's correspondence [2 of 4]1898-1899 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Constantin Dillon's correspondence [3 of 4]1901-1906 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Constantin Dillon's correspondence [4 of 4]1913-1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Constantin Dillon's correspondence with British Authorities1922 Apr. 14 -Nov. 23 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Constantin Dillon's correspondence [miscellaneous]1933-1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Constantin Dillon's personal papers1898- 1902 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cuairan, Florencio [pencil drawing]1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Note: incl. a letter dated 1951 Oct. 26.
  - Dillon's E..J. correspondence [1 of 2]1900-1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Note: incl. photos.
  - Dillon's E..J. correspondence [2 of 2]1928-undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dillon's Obituaries [1 of 3]1933 June 7 - June 10; includes undated materials (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Refers to: Blowitz; President Obregon; Dreyfus; Mr. Frank McDonagh; Mr. T. D. Sullivaan; Count Witte; M. Venizelos; M. Take Jonescu; Miss Kathleen Ireland; Catherine Vareshina; Mr. Constantine Dillon; Mr. Gladstone; Mr. Thomas MacCenelly; Dr. Kent; J. Hall Richardson; T. P. O'Connor; Viscount Burnham; Lloyd George; Lord Riddell; Sir Donald Mackenzie Wallace; Sir Valentine Chirol; Mr. J. D. Bourchier; Mr. Wickham Steed; W. T. Sread. Note: some materials are in Spanish.
  - Dillon's Obituaries [2 of 3]1933 June 11 - 1934 Sept. 28 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dillon's Obituaries [3 of 3]1933 June 9 - June 25 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Harold G. Dillon's correspondence1903 March [n.d.] - 1922 March [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Harold G. Dillon's Passport1916 Dec. [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Harold G. Dillon's personal papers [1 of 2]1889-1916 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    note: some materials are in French and Russian.
  - Harold G. Dillon's personal papers [2 of 2]1917-1921 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Note: some materials are in French and Russian.
  - Harold G. Dillon's Pocket Diary1909-1910 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - On Dillon's Biography1921 [n.d.] - 1954 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Includes a typescript, a manuscript.
  - Postcards [1 of 3]1911-1924 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Postcards [2 of 3]1925-1932 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Postcards [3 of 3]Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Vareshina's Katya correspondence1937-1952 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Note: incl. presscuttings, catalogs of exibitons.
  - Vladimir Dillon's correspondence1921 May 10 - 1955 Jan. 28 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Vladimir Dillon's personal papers1896-1899 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Youthful Poetry1870; incl. undated materials (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Note: some texts are in Latin and French.
  - Miscelaneous [1 of 3]1893-1937 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Miscelaneous [2 of 3]1908-1928 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Miscelaneous [3 of 3]Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Miscelaneous [3 of 3]Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bank Accounts1933 Oct 31 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bank Statements 1917 June 30 - 1917 Oct 30 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Note: materilas are in Russian.
  - Constantine Dillon's Correspondence with Carter & Swallow1933 Feb 8 - 1935 Oct 9 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Constantine Dillon's Correspondence with Carter & Swallow1933 Feb 8 - 1935 Oct 9 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Constantine Dillon's Correspondence1905 Aug 7 - 1957; includes undated materials (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Includes: photos, caricatures, telegrams.Note: some materials are in German and Russian.
  - Constantine Dillon's Personal Documents1887 March 23 - 1958 Dec 24 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Copies of the Pages fron the Book "Peterborough Court.The Story of the Daily Telegraph"1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Copy of the Letter of Protest to Foreign Office1900 Jan 26 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Diary Notes1913 March [n.d.]- 1917 July [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - E. J. Dillon's Correspondence [miscellaneous] [1 of 2]1892 Aug 30 - 1923 Aug 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Note: some materials are in French, German, Italian.
  - E. J. Dillon's Correspondence [miscellaneous] [2 of 2]1924 June 16 - 1938 Dec 18; includes undated materials (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Note: some materials are in French and Spanish.
  - Elena Dillon's Correspondence1897 March 30 - 1920 May 31 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Kathleen Dillon's Correspondence1914 July 30 - 1935 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Lillie Dillon's Correspondence1896 Nov 30 - 1920 Feb 21 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Lucie Dillon's Correspondence1961 Feb 2 - March 4 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mary Dillon's Correspondence1888 Apr 3 - 1903 Dec [n.d.]; includes undated materials (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Belgian Order 1880 Sep [n.d.] - 1920 Jan 5 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Includes: certificates, an invitation, passes, an off-print.Note: some materials are in French.
  - Correspondence [miscellaneous]1917 July 17; includes undated materials (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - E. J. Dillon's Correspondence with Spurgeon, John1918 Nov 13 - 1919 June 8 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Includes telegrams.
  - E. J. Dillon's Passport1885 Dec 24 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - E. J. Dillon's Personal Documents1884 Feb 24 - 1918 Apr 19 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Note: in Russian and French.
  - E. J. Dillon's Will1933 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Invitations1900 July 25 - 1925 July 14; includes undated materials (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - JournalUndated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Legal correspondence [miscellaneous]1874 July 15 - 1933 Feb 22 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Includes: a postcard, uncashed checks, bills.Note: some materials are in Russian.
  - Miscellaneous1904 - 1918; includes undated materials (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Stocks1918 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Note: materials are in German.
  - Summary of Executorship Accounts1935 Sep 30 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Telegrams189[?] - 1935 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Note: some materials are in Arabic.
  - Temple Yacht Club Membership1891 - 1927 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Includes a press-cutting in German.
  - The Centenary Suplement of "The Daily Telegraph"Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Vladimir E. Dillon's Will1944 Aug 29 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Note: materials are in Spanish.
  - Col. Wiljamovsky's [Constantine Dillon's Brother-in-Law] Letters 1919 July [n.d.] - 1922 June [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Eddie Dillon; postcards1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Inventory of Books [1 of 2]Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Inventory of Books [2 of 2]Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Inventories of Different Articles1924; includes undated materials (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Kathleen Dillon's Correspondence with Officials [1 of 2]1938 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Kathleen Dillon's Correspondence with Officials [2 of 2]1938 - 1939 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Kathleen Dillon's Passport1919 May 13 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - List of Diaries & DictionariesUndated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Official Letters Concerning Kathleen Dillon's Estate1960 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Official & Recomendation Letters, Card-passes [1 of 2]1876 - 1919 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Note: in different foreign languages.
  - Official & Recomendation Letters, Card-passes [2 of 2]1918 - 1935 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Memoirs [1 of 8]1869 - 1874 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Memoirs [2 of 8]Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Memoirs [3 of 8]Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Memoirs [4 of 8]Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Memoirs [5 of 8]Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Memoirs [6 of 8]Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Memoirs [7 of 8]Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Memoirs [8 of 8]Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Memoirs [miscellaneous]1894; includes undated materials (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Includes a letter, an off-print.Note: some materials are in German.
- Series 8. Press Cuttings, 2 linear ft.
  - Articles on Portsmouth Peace Conference1905 Aug 7 - 1905 Sep 6 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ctholicism in Germany1903 Aug 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Count Witte's Memoirs1921 March [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Darkest Russia" Review with E. J. Dillons Article1893 June 1 - 1893 Aug 11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dillon's Articles in Polish1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Note: in Polish.
  - Greece [Venizelos]1912 Dec 13 - -1916 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Note: some materials are in French.
  - Hoover's Record1931 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hungarian Clergy1892 Jan 1 - 1893 Apr 14 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Interview with E. J. Dillon1924 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Jews1892 Aug 19 - 1921 Aug 26; includes undated materials (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Jews in Austria1894 Apr 18 - 1894 Sep 16 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Jews in Russia and Roumania1890 Apr 4 - 1908 Jan 23 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Life of the Young Prince1918 Aug 30 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mexico [Obregon]1920 Sep [n.d.] - 1924 July [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Nicholas II1908 - 1918 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Russia1906 -1911 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Note: some materials are in German and Russian.
  - Russia, Austria and Albanian Problem1913 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Sazonoff, M.1912 - 1919 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Sects1904 March 7/20 - Nov 12 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Stolypin1906 - 1912 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Attempt of Assassination of Tsar1907 May 13 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Austria1909 - 1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Britain and Middle East1921 June 26 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - California1919 Dec [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence [miscellaneous]1893 July 15 - 1924 July 5; includes undated materials (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Note: some materials are in French, Italian and Spanish.
  - Death of Taaffe1895 Nov 29 - 1895 Dec 21 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - France1893 - 1932 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Note: some materials are in German.
  - Galicia1921 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Note: in Ukrain.
  - Germany [1 of 2]1914; includes undated materials (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Germany [2 of 2]1933 March 22-25 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - India1909 June 26-28 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Izvolsky & Aehrenthal1909 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Jesus1925 Dec 13 - 1926 July 29 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Jewish World Plot1921 Aug 16-18 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Lower California1922 Feb [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Marrige & Divorce1890 - 1894 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Note: in German and Russian.
  - Menshikoff's Article1908 Aug 2- 1908 Nov 11 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Mr. Gandhi and the Swarajists1924 June20 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - On Dillon's Dissertation1881 - 1893 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Palestine1921 Nov 8 - 1922 Feb 16 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Persons [1 of 2]1902 -1910 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Note: some materilas are in French, German, and Spanish.
  - Persons [2 of 2]1911 -1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Note: some materilas are in French and German.
  - Religion1893 March 29 - 1916 Jan [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Note: some materilas are in German and Russian.
  - Russia Painted by Herself1904 Aug 9 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Russian Society1899 Aug 19-26; includes undated materials (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The Conference of Ambassadors1912 -1913 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - The Monks of Solovetsky1908 Aug 24 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - The Pressure of Want1916 Jan 23 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - The War. How Will It End? 1912 May 27 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Balkan Question1908 - 1913 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cuttings from Mexican Papers1915 June [n.d.] - July [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dillon's Telegrams Reproduced in Vienna Papers1909 - 1913 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Note: some materials are in Russian and German.
  - Miscellaneous [1 of 3]1888 - 1910 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous [2 of 3]1911 - 1914 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous [3 of 3]1919 - 1936 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Note: some materials are in German and Italian
  - Persia1910 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Portugal1908 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Roumania1903 - 1925 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sakhalin1905 - 1908 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Inside History of the Peace Conference1921 May 11 - Aug 20 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Turkey1911 - 1913 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Reproductions of Dillon's Articles and Telegrams; 1901 - 1910 1901 - 1910 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Reproductions of Dillon's Articles and Telegrams in Greek 1909 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Note: in Greek.
  - Reproductions of Dillon's Articles and Telegrams in Russian 1909 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Reproductions of Dillon's Articles and Telegrams; 1911 1911 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Reproductions of Dillon's Articles and Telegrams; 1912 1912 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reproductions of Dillon's Articles and Telegrams; 1920 [1 of 2]1920 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reproductions of Dillon's Articles and Telegrams; 1920 [2 of 2]1920 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Reproductions of Dillon's Articles and Telegrams; 1921 - 19281921 -1928 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Anglo-Russian Convention1904 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Darkest Russia1891 - 1893, Newspapers (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers & Press-cuttings, 1883 - 19171883 - 1917 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers & Press-cuttings, 1920 - 19311920 - 1931 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Parliamentary Bill1911 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Peace Treaty1919 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Press-cuttings, 1905 - 19061905 - 1906 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Press-cuttings, 1908 - 19101908 - 1910 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Press-cuttings, 19131913 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Note: some materials are in French and Italian.
  - Press-cuttings, 19161916 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Radziwill, Dorothy D.1920 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series 9. Published Items, 2.5 linear ft.
  - Subseries 1. Sheet Music, 1.5 linear ft.
    - A1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bach, J. S.n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Borodine, A.1889 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - B - C1920 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dn.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Fn.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Folk Songsn.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Gn.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Grieg, Edvard1919 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Hn.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - K - Mn.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous [1 of 2 ]n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous [2 of 2 ]n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Operasn.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Pn.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Rn.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Romantic Songs [1 of 4]n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Romantic Songs [2 of 4]n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Romantic Songs [3 of 4]n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Romantic Songs [4 of 4]1921 Oct. [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Sn.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Songs [1 of 3]1893; includes undated materials (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Songs [2 of 3]n.d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Songs [3 of 3]1877 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Songs [3 of 3]1877 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Tn.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Vertinskyn.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Violin and Piano Music [1 of 7]n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Violin and Piano Music [2 of 7]n.d. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Violin and Piano Music [3 of 7]n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Violin and Piano Music [4 of 7]n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Violin and Piano Music [5 of 7]n.d. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Violin and Piano Music [6 of 7]n.d. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Violin and Piano Music [7 of 7]n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2. Various Aspects of Russian Life, 1 linear ft.
    - "British Russian Gazette and Trade outlook"1924 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "Niva", Literary Magazine [1 of 4] 1913 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "Niva", Literary Magazine [2 of 4] 1913 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "Niva", Literary Magazine [3 of 4] 1913 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "Niva", Literary Magazine [4 of 4] 1916 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Opera & Ballet Programmes [1 of 6]1933 - 1935 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Opera & Ballet Programmes [2 of 6]n. d. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Opera & Ballet Programmes [3 of 6]1931 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Opera & Ballet Programmes [4 of 6]1931 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Opera & Ballet Programmes [5 of 6]1933 - 1935 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Note: includes press-cutting.
    - "Perezvony", Literary Magazine 1926 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "Theater and Life", Magazine [1 of 9] 1929 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "Theater and Life", Magazine [2 of 9] 1929 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "Theater and Life", Magazine [3 of 9] 1929 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Theater and Life", Magazine [4 of 9] 1930 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "Theater and Life", Magazine [5 of 9] 1931 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "Theater and Life", Magazine [6 of 9] 1932 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "Theater and Life", Magazine [7 of 9] 1933 - 1934 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "Theater and Life", Magazine [8 of 9] 1934 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "Theater and Life", Magazine [9 of 9] 1935 - 1936 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "Zelionaya Palochka", Children's Literary Magazine1920 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "Zelionaya Palochka", Children's Literary Magazine1920 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Series 10. Scrapbooks and Journals, 2 linear ft.
  The contents of this series are largely bound volumes filled with newsclippings, some of which contain marginalia.
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1884 - 18871884 - 1887 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1885- 18891885 - 1889 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 18861886 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1887 - 881887 - 88 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1888 - 891888 - 89 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1892 - 19101892 - 1910 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Note: some materials are in Geraman and Russian.
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1905 - 19061905 - 1906 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1905 - 19081905 - 1908 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1911 - 12 [1 of 2]1911 - 12 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1911 - 12 [2 of 2]1911 - 12 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 19121912 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1913 Jan. 23 - March 311913 Jan. 23 - March 31 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1913 Apr. 1 - May 11913 Apr. 1 - May 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1913 May 2 - July 181913 May 2 - July 18 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1914 Sept. 2 - 1915 May 131914 Sept. 2 - 1915 May 13 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1915 May 14 - 1916 Aug. 81915 May 14 - 1916 Aug. 8 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1916 Aug. 19 - 1917 Sept. 71916 Aug. 19 - 1917 Sept. 7 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 19181918 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1919 Jan. 3 - July 291919 Jan. 3 - July 29 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1919 - 19201919 - 1920 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1920 May 9 - Dec. 191920 May 9 - Dec. 19 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1920 - 19231920 - 1923 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 19211921 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Note: some materials are in German, Polish and Spanish.
  - Scrap & Newscutting Book, 1921 - 19221921 - 1922 (Box 5, Folder 6)